CraftingLevels Addon for FFXI
Author

Faceless
Version

8675.3.09
Description

The CraftingLevels addon for Final Fantasy XI (FFXI) tracks and displays the current levels of all crafting skills (Fishing, Woodworking, Smithing, Goldsmithing, Clothcraft, Leathercraft, Bonecraft, Alchemy, Cooking). The addon provides a configurable display window to show the crafting levels and allows you to customize font settings, position, and size.
Features

    Tracks and displays crafting skill levels in real time by keeping track of progress of skill ups and will autoupdate to the correct level once you level up the first time then stay accurate..
    Supports nine crafting skills: Fishing, Woodworking, Smithing, Goldsmithing, Clothcraft, Leathercraft, Bonecraft, Alchemy, and Cooking.
    Customizable display with options for font type, size, and window position.
    Toggle visibility of the display box.
    Command-based settings adjustments (font, font size, position).

Installation

    Download and extract the CraftingLevels addon into your FFXI addons directory.
    The directory structure should be:

    addons/CraftingLevels/
    ├── CraftingLevels.lua
    └── README.md

Configuration

Upon loading, the addon will read and save crafting skill levels from a configuration file. The following options can be configured:

    skill_levels: A table that stores the levels of the nine crafting skills. By default, they are set to 0.0.
    font: Font to use for the display text. Default is 'Rockwell'.
    fontsize: Font size for the display text. Default is 10.
    pos: Position of the display window on the screen, represented as an {x, y} coordinate. Default is {x = 0, y = 700}.

These settings can be changed in-game via commands.
Commands

The addon supports the following commands:

    /craftinglevels toggle
    Toggles the visibility of the crafting levels display.

    /craftinglevels hidezero
    Toggles the visibility of crafts with zero skill level.

    /craftinglevels setfont [font name]
    Changes the font used in the display. Example usage: /craftinglevels setfont Arial.

    /craftinglevels setfontsize [size]
    Changes the font size used in the display. Example usage: /craftinglevels setfontsize 14.

    /craftinglevels setpos [x] [y]
    Changes the position of the display box. Example usage: /craftinglevels setpos 100 200.

Events

    Login: The addon will initialize and display crafting levels when you log in to the game or change jobs.
    Job Change: The addon will refresh the crafting levels display upon job changes.
    Incoming Text: The addon updates the crafting skill levels when a skill-up occurs.

How It Works

    Upon initialization, the addon loads the saved crafting skill levels from the configuration file.
    If a crafting skill has leveled up during gameplay, the addon updates the displayed levels in real-time.
    The display box can be moved, and its settings (font, size, position) can be customized using the provided commands.

Troubleshooting

    If the crafting levels are not displaying, ensure that the addon is correctly installed in your FFXI addons directory.
    If the display is not visible after login, try toggling it with /craftinglevels toggle.

Credits

    Faceless (Developer)

License

This addon is released under the MIT License. Feel free to use, modify, and distribute.

This readme should give users a clear understanding of the CraftingLevels addon, its features, and how to install and configure it.
